[Music]
hey everyone this is a slightly
different film than normal this is a
rebel wisdom investigation and it's I've
been in journalism for about 20 years
and this is one of the most fascinating
interesting stories that I found in my
whole time doing this work and it's so
important for right now so it's about
the recent interview with the conspiracy
researcher David Icke on the London real
YouTube channel and then it being taken
down by YouTube and it's got everything
it's got all of the questions about the
tech platforms it's got all of the
questions about free speech it's got all
of the questions about why these issues
are becoming so important right now
in in the wake of the pandemic and I'm
gonna lay it out I'm going to lay out
the investigation that I've gone through
I'm gonna lay out the evidence that I
found I'm gonna put links to the
evidence I'm going to do it as carefully
as I can and I also want to say that I
have approached London real Brian Rose
the interviewer for a response to this
I've also asked David Icke for an
interview haven't heard anything back
yet but if I do hear anything I'm gonna
put it into the film and why this is
really important as it brings together
so many of the issues that we've been
talking about on the channel why we
can't trust anything why we can't make
sense of the world and how we come to
truth these are hugely important issues
and this one case seems to epitomize
like all of the problems and all of the
difficulties in this area so it's not
just London real there's also going to
be criticisms of the big tech platforms
including YouTube in this as well so I'm
a little bit concerned about this being
taken down a few different reasons one
I'm going to use some clips from London
real and they have been getting calling
and copyright and getting those taken
down elsewhere on YouTube I think I have
a defense for that this is fair dealing
it's newsworthy so in the end I think
the process YouTube take a long time to
go through this process I think in the
end it would be reviewed and okayed but
in the meantime it could easily be taken
down for a while so what I'm going to do
is put a copy of this film on our
website the rebel wisdom website and
also there is a written piece as well
that I'm putting on my medium so you can
also potentially download this keep it
and then put it out elsewhere as well so
starting at the beginning with the
timeline on the 6th of April London real
did an interview with David Icke who is
a veteran conspiracy researcher in it
Icke claimed that the covert 19 was a
hoax he said that it was basically I'm
summarizing here it's a very complex
argument you can find the interview
elsewhere on it's been taken down from
YouTube but it's available in quite a
lot of places and I think it's fair to
summarize it as that Co vid was a hoax
it was a cover for a murderous global
cult determined to bring in a fascist
state we're using 5g to engineer a mask
hull and he also said that if humanity
didn't get off its knees now then human
life as we know it is over this was the
second most popular livestream of the
day and YouTube took it down the next
day after there was a big public outcry
it was big news on the BBC it was big
news on a lot of other media channels
and in the aftermath of it Brian Rose
who was the interviewer and the host and
the owner of London real said this is a
clear breach of human rights as a clear
free speech issue
putting the BBC out of business the last
time I checked as humans in this world
we have this little thing in America we
call it the First Amendment called
freedom of speech as in you're allowed
to say what you want to say and this
other thing in the same amendment called
freedom of press as in I can print what
I want to print he announced that he
would interview Icke again on the 3rd of
May which as I'm recording this is
tomorrow Sunday he wanted it to be the
biggest live stream in internet history
up to a million people and also shortly
after that he launched what he called
the digital freedom platform which was
designed so he said to pay for the live
stream of the Icke interview $100,000 at
first hit that within a day the amount
has been going up and up and up and
right now it's approaching a million
dollars for the digital freedom platform
which we'll go into in a second there
are some things I have sympathy with
Bryan rose I think the tech platforms
are massively unaccountable as he says
YouTube made a huge amount of money in
partnership with him over quite a long
time because YouTube streams ads and
shares the ad revenue with the creator
so YouTube has made a lot of money out
of London really over a long time Bryan
is very upset that they basically told
the BBC that they were taking it down
before they talked to him about it I
completely agree there are real issues
with the tech platforms that going to
come to in a bit huge problems around
free speech and unaccountability but
what I want to concentrate on right now
is how on the other side these concerns
about free speech can also be weaponized
so as you can see from the crowd funder
which is hosted on the London real
website it's not on an independent
crowdfunding platform it's on the London
real website it's framed as the digital
freedom platform by the people for the
people
it was framed as a way of getting banned
content out there without going through
the big tech platforms and Brian said
very clearly I'll play a clip now where
he said that it's independent of London
real okay what an incredible day here
had London real world headquarters Wow
the point is is this is a
separate entity that lives on past us
that is independently funded so we don't
draw any of this money this is set up as
an independent platform so that has
nothing to do with London real and the
other thing is is you don't have to
contribute if you don't want to you
don't have to step up and fight on the
front lines so if you click into the
terms and conditions of this digital
freedom platform it says further down
that it will be wholly owned by
long-stem limited so you've got a
company's house and check who long-stem
limited us a long-stem limited from what
I can tell on Companies House again I'll
put the screenshots here is the entity
that owns London real and has one single
shareholder and that shareholder is
Brian rose and then London real launched
the digital freedom platform with a
couple of interviews with dr. Butare and
a couple of other ones so it's actually
operational if you have a look at it
it's within the London real website it's
not a separate platform it's housed
within the London real website next to
the ads for London reals high value
courses which we'll come to in a second
and also while I was making this a few
other people have started picking up on
this story there's a few videos coming
out already and I'm a player clip from
one of them where they've gone into the
source code and found that what is the
the stream for the digital freedom
platform seems to be coming from a
YouTube competitor called dailymotion
here comes the main point of this whole
video I wanted to find out how much does
the Bentley really cost so I went
through the source code of his website
to potentially find which hosting he
uses for the stream after a minute or
two of scrolling I finally found it wait
for it please
it's daily motion calm for those of you
who don't know
dailymotion is basically an alternative
to YouTube
same thing basically a free video
streaming platform now at this point I
still thought he might be paying for
streaming so I went to their website to
see if there's some custom streaming
feature that they are offering and how
much does it cost as you can see there
are two plans available and starter is
free but when says contact us so I
thought okay I'm going to contact them
and ask just for the sake of this video
since he is probably using that advanced
plan and even if he's not he can always
claim that what he's using and that it
costs before I did that I clicked the
offers tab and I was shocked starter
plan says free advanced offers says oh
look at that
free as well
so I've messaged dailymotion to ask them
if this is the case and we'll see what
they say so the digital freedom platform
is hosted within the London real website
and what they've started doing recently
is these interviews with the so-called
band figures but if you check out most
of these people are not actually banned
on Facebook or YouTube some are some
aren't but most of them aren't they're
now starting to play like 10-minute
clips on YouTube and then you have to go
to the website to watch the rest of it
what's important to point out is that as
Rose has said in the past despite the
fact they've got 1.7 million YouTube
subscribers it's very hard to monetize
and make a business off YouTube so what
they generally do the the high value
products are the courses where the
Business Accelerator and the learning to
podcast course both of which cost about
three thousand five hundred dollars for
an eight-week course incidentally I've
also been sent this link to the website
scam guard where there are 20 negative
reviews of London reals courses again
I'll put the link in the show notes
below so you can check this out yourself
I don't have no way of verifying it
again I've asked Brian for a response so
an interesting thing to understand now
is what a brilliant business move this
is so basically Brian Rose has managed
to persuade a lot of people to pay for
him to host his controversial content
off youtube so therefore reducing the
risk of getting d platform because he's
not hosting the livestream with David
Icke on YouTube anymore so he's
protecting himself while also getting
people to pay to move his content onto
the more important real estate the more
valuable real estate so we've already
talked about long-stem limited which is
the company that owns london real the
most recent filings show that Brian Rose
is the sole shareholder I've asked him
again if that's still the case and if I
hear anything I'll update that
information but you can also check at
Companies House the latest accounts for
companies if you check the latest
accounts for long-stem limited it looks
like they're in quite serious debt and
again I'll put the link to the the
accounts in
the show notes below so you can check
that out for yourself so there seems to
be a growing backlash there are people
who are posting videos on YouTube
calling out what's going on and also a
lot of people posting comments
criticizing or asking questions and it
seems that those comments are being
deleted again I've asked Brian Rose and
London real to confirm or deny whether
they're deleting comments
okay so that concludes the journalistic
investigation part again like I say I've
put all of those claims to Brian Rose
we'll see what happens we'll see what
response we get and now I want to kind
of expand it out and talk about why I
think this is such an important topic
and why it just flags up so many of the
massive issues that we're getting right
now on both sides the censorship of the
tech platforms and in the backlash that
it's creating and these are huge issues
I don't think anyone knows what the
solution is to this I've wrestled with
this a huge amount so I worked for 20
years in kind of traditional media I was
at the BBC started on BBC News Online
then moved to Channel 4 News for many
years mostly of the foreign producer and
shooter and editor as well so I also
then moved a left channel for news
formerly in about 2012 started making
documentaries for mostly for the Emmy
award-winning unreported world then in
2018 I started rebel wisdom the YouTube
media channel that you're watching this
on and so for two years I mean the
reason for doing that was to tell
stories that I wasn't able to tell and
bring perspectives like it wasn't able
to bring in the mainstream media so I'm
really passionate about the potential of
alternative media for showing up the
holes in the mainstream the breakout
film for rebel wisdom was called a
glitch in the matrix and that's now have
four million views on on YouTube it was
uploaded to Jordan Peterson site and the
main thrust of that film was one of the
holes in the mainstream worldview what
is the kind of groupthink in the media
what are the problems with the what are
the problems with the traditional media
what is what are the values of the
alternative media and this kind of
general realization that I was coming to
this was a really important issue of all
these perspectives were being left out
and it's becoming increasingly important
now so the big picture framing I would
say is that we're in this kind of
interregnum period between two worlds
we've let the old gatekeepers
losing their power increasingly fast
like this is and for lots of good
reasons as I pointed out in previous
films
lots of journalism became self-satisfied
it became arrogant it became corrupt it
became unaccountable alignment of
interests all of that I won't go into
that right now
but we're in this really so and those
gatekeepers are losing their power and
ever increasing rate but what we don't
have is you can imagine there might be
some kind of decentralized Network way
of coming to truth Democratic way of
coming to truth that could emerge on the
other side we're not there yet so what
we have is this ecosystem of
misinformation of bad actors of no
accountability and all of these things
are getting worse and worse and worse
and the actions of the tech companies
like really heavy-handed censorship and
just saying oh no we need to follow the
official narratives is making a bad
situation infinitely worse so this is a
really dangerous situation and I think
it's going to get worse and now we're
actually getting to the point where even
in magazines like the Atlantic we're
getting questions like does China have
the right attitude to free speech so I
want to be able to carry on asking
difficult questions and challenging
narratives on rebel wisdom we put out a
piece recently talking about the
unanswered questions in the Jeffrey
Epstein case there are huge questions
about the origin of the virus that are
genuine but I want to be able to ask and
I will not be told what I can and cannot
discuss by the big tech companies
so coming back to London real a little
bit of background that might help people
kind of understand if you're not
familiar with them I've been following
them for quite a while they interview a
lot of really interesting people some of
whom I've also interviewed people like
gabble Matt a people at Jordan Peterson
so London real is entirely framed around
Bryan Rose and he's a fascinating
character and the whole the whole of
London real is is this very interesting
mix of kind of high-octane
take-no-prisoners business advice
my next accelerate of course is starting
soon but also talks about New Age stuff
rose himself has shown a lot of empathy
in the past talking about his struggles
with alcoholism while I'm training in
New York City I just these demons kind
of come out and you know that would that
all happened you know I remember I was
on that bike you can't say there's a
part in the sequence where I'm training
on a bike and I go really to a state of
physical exhaustion and I was actually
crying on that bike
it looks like I'm sweating I was crying
my whole crew freaked out I never seen
you cry before and I was literally kind
of falling apart while I was there in
New York and I was in these village
where I was first offered heroin and I
lived in this heroin addiction London
real slogan is transform yourself and
rebel wisdom slogan is inspire ignite
transform so there's a really and we're
actually passionate about a lot of the
same things like transformation of
consciousness I've met Brian Rose once I
went there when Jamie wheel was
interviewed on London real a little
while ago and I've always been intrigued
I'm still intrigued I think my sense is
that there are two at least two
different forces maybe more operating
within Brian Rose my concern right now
is that one of them has got the upper
hand and I think to be honest and I'm
going to sketch out why I think this I
think what he is doing right now he's
incredibly dangerous and I think it's
really important that we use our free
speech to call out people who we think
are being irresponsible because right
now if we don't do this if we don't use
our free speech and somehow create some
kind of
accountability then what's going to
happen is that the big tech platforms
are going to take those decisions for us
that we're going to if we don't use free
speech with responsibility we're gonna
lose it that's what I fear happening
right now because we all know there's a
huge bias towards free speech absolute
ISM on YouTube I can't I get it I get
where that comes from but it's naive
because we all know that free speech
does not include shouting fire in a
crowded theater it's quite an outdated
analogy nowadays but the idea if you
shout fire in a crowded theater you
start a stampede people get injured so
that we all know there are
responsibilities in free speech we know
that in our relationships there are free
speech is nested within ethical
framework and so what we are finding is
that we're at the mercy of the
individual ethical decisions of each of
the curators themselves and some
curators have more power than others and
so this is a this is a moral dilemma
that no one really knows the answer to
and a lot of people are grappling with
right now so I'm going to talk
specifically about the David Icke
interview and the moral challenges that
that brings up because clearly shouting
fire in a crowded theater in the middle
of a global pandemic while people are at
home while people are vulnerable telling
them while there are attacks on 5-g
masks around the country
just imagine the attack potentially on
5-g engineer so we're putting these up
as well this definitely is covered by
shouting fire in a crowded theater but
also if David Icke is right let's still
man him that this is actually a whole
plot for global fascist evil cult this
is information that needs to come out so
that there is a defense to be made of
featuring David Icke but then you have
to factor in how you frame him how you
deliver it how you give people the the
tools to make those decisions and how
you as a curator as someone who is
inviting them onto your platform how you
treat that interview those are hugely
important issues and we used to have a
method for that or we used to have ways
of dealing with that and we don't any
so after the interview Brian Rose was
framing this as I don't agree with David
Icke but this is a freedom of speech
issue he has every right to have his
voice heard which I can agree with but
it's not really true if you actually
look at what Brian Rose asked David Icke
in the interview and I will bring up the
questions now
he was framing David Icke as speaking
the truth Tibbett what's it like to
watch 30 years of what you've been
working on all come to fruition
prediction reality in three weeks what's
it like you've got to be really aware of
people's motivations of people's ethical
motivations of where they're the words
are true again I much prefer to be
having this conversation with Brian Rose
I've asked him now four or five times
for an interview and he hasn't responded
and free speech without accountability
free speech without those ideas being
challenged is not free speech it's
propaganda the whole point of free
speech is that those ideas then get
challenged in the marketplace and the
problem with so much of the conspiracy
narrative is that it's happening in this
closed ecosystem it's not being taken
seriously by the mainstream and I think
the mainstream is going to have to start
taking it seriously it's not going to be
able to keep gatekeeping all of this out
that's old thinking which I'll come to
in a second I think engaging with David
Icke is necessary I've actually got a
little bit of a soft spot for David Icke
because he's been saying what he's been
saying about this fascist cult for at
least since the the early 90s
and he hasn't changed his message even
when he was saying things like 12-foot
lizards a rule in the world Saturn
Saturn's rings are a mind-control device
the moon is a hollow spaceship all of
these things he's he's never changed
what he's saying even when what he was
saying was making him more unpopular and
was making people think he was crazy he
has he's had the integrity to at least
stick to the conspiracy theories that he
believes rather than just changing it
for what was popular and I also think
that he he's not
necessarily a fringe figure in any
meaningful way he fills out stadiums
across the country up until now the
traditional media has been able to to
gate keep him get keep him out I don't
think that's possible anymore I also
don't think now that he's done this very
popular video on London real up until
that point you could argue whether it
was a the right editorial decision to
invite David Icke onto a platform in the
middle of a global pandemic we can argue
about that right now I think there is an
editorial justification for interviewing
David Icke in a responsible way and
putting to him some of the things that
he said in the past saying hang on David
you said something similar before and it
didn't seem to pan out do you also still
believe this and still believe this and
also what you're saying about this being
a hoax doesn't seem to add up and what
about 5g and the fact that actually the
the map of 5g doesn't really overlap
with the with where the virus has been
strongest Iran didn't have 5g Italy
didn't have 5g and you also keep saying
that Wuhan was the first place in China
to get 5g that's kind of true but it's
not really true because actually Wuhan
was one of 10 cities where they were
doing trials of 5g so all of these
things need to be all of these questions
need to be raised and how this is
supposed to happen and used to happen in
a functioning media ecosystem is that
you would someone would do their
research they would go into an into an
interview with someone and you would
interview someone and you would put
those questions they would then
potentially go onto another show that
person would do their job as well they
would watch all the previous interview
to that person they'd find out what
questions they've been asked what
questions they haven't been asked what
questions they gave really good answers
to what they didn't give good answers to
and then you have this process of
weeding out people with with truth and
though the people who were bluffing or
who were just not trustable would be
weeded out this is not happening right
now what we're having is these
closed-loop ecosystems where
and what London real is doing now is
making a big play to be a central node
in the conspiracy ecosystem you know I
was broadcasting for nine years but now
I'm starting to understand what it feels
like to be in your shoes Alex maybe you
can start off by giving them giving me
some advice here what is actually
happening to me because I'm not used to
this space and maybe you can tell me
what's actually going on with me and
what what should I expect to happen in
the few and the following months and
maybe year
well Brian your problem is your
authentic your real I'm never met in
person watching for years you come
across as real I feel good looking at
you my gut you know that's a thousand
times more powerful than my conscious
mind that guts really your subconscious
mind says this is a guy I can trust and
then there's the issue of editorial
judgment when I was at BBC in channel 4
we would spend like these questions are
hugely nuanced there are no absolutes
like why you interview someone how you
do it protection of sources who is
impacted by you broadcasting a certain
story all of these ethical questions
come up with every with every story and
what I learnt and kind of surprised me
to learn is that there are that every
single decision is contextual like there
are no absolutes but these are rules of
engagement that have evolved over many
many years probably centuries I mean the
basic values of functioning journalism
is that you strive for accuracy you try
and make sure that you get both sides of
the story or at least allow people to
respond these are like values that are
pretty much non-existent as far as I can
see in the alternative media but coming
back so we now have the tech platforms
trying to ad-hoc makeup editorial
decisions on the fly and I just don't
see how they are going to be able to do
this like I want to be able to interview
David Icke I've asked David Icke for an
interview I think there's an editorial
reason for doing it and I want to be
able to broadcast that interview David
Icke I don't want them to be able to
turn around and say sorry he's
off-limits who the fuck are you to make
that decision for me
how is YouTube going to be able to make
a decision of whether this particular
interview with David Icke was
responsibly conducted and this
interviewed David Icke was not
responsibly conducted are they able to
make those decisions it seems highly
unlikely but that's the place that
they're in so London real have made a
full-on pivot into conspiracy an
alternative narrative and some of these
narratives are necessary like we don't
know we like we cannot just stick with
the mainstream narratives and also some
of these narratives that are being kind
of seen as conspiracy are turning out to
have more than a little bit of truth the
idea that the virus could have come from
the lab has gone from being crazy to
actually there's a lot of strong
circumstantial evidence that lead us to
suggest that that there might be some
truth in that what was the
gain-of-function research that was being
done in wuhan all of these questions
need to be examined and also what you
have is this weird dynamic of any
medical figure who is willing to say
counter-narrative stuff is getting
massively signal boosted so you get
people like doctor Butare you get people
like dr. Kaufman saying and they fit
both featured on London real getting
huge amounts of views and this is a
weird part of the incentive landscape
dr. Kaufman he's not a medical doctor
he's a psychiatrist
and yet he's making like very strong
claims about medicine like some of the
we need to have we need to be asking
point we need to be asking the right
questions of some of these figures and
at the moment we've got this weird
accountability problem where anyone
saying anything counter-narrative is is
not being held to account and this is I
think this is potentially a fatal flaw
in our information ecosystem but we also
know that some of these claims are
really important and have turned out to
be true
take dr. Cameron Kyle siddell he put out
a film a couple of weeks ago saying that
what he was seeing the doctor from New
York he put out a film saying that what
he was seeing was something more like
altitude sickness in his patients rather
than pneumonia and he said that maybe
why over 50
people are being put onto ventilators
are still dying because it's not the
right we're not treating people the
right way and and now two weeks on what
he was saying is now being repeated by a
lot of people and even a recent piece in
New York Magazine basically quoted him
and said that this is something that we
so basically we can't cut down we can't
immediately discount these alternative
voices we need some kind of filtering
system for them we don't have it we
don't know what one might even look like
so we've got this crazy dilemma where on
one side we've got the tech platforms
basically saying anything that is not
mainstream and institutional is not
accepted and then on the other side
you've got this kind of free-for-all
where free speech can be weaponized
claims of censorship can be weaponized
to avoid any kind of accountability and
then you've got bad actors exploiting
all of this at the same time it's an
absolute clusterfuck and why I feel
really really passionately about this
especially about London real is because
we've touched on a lot of these issues
over quite a long time particularly
psychedelic narcissism which I think is
a big factor in this and the information
ecology and I just want to repeat if we
don't find a solution we everyone if we
don't find a solution to this problem
the solution will be imposed by the big
tech platforms and we're not going to
like it so I'm going to carry on
following this story I think it's one of
the most fascinating ones I've ever
covered I think it's such an important
one for where we're at right now so if
you know anything about this store if
you're a whistleblower and you want to
get in touch then mail me at this email
address here I promise to keep your
details confidential I just want to end
with one question to Brian rose and
that's how would you feel if I went to
America and started broadcasting
dangerous misinformation during the
country's worst crisis while sitting in
front of an American flag so if you're
going to carry on doing what you're
doing can you at least take the British
flags down so what happens next we've
just launched a hashtag called rebel
wisdom army and we're launching a
crowdfunding campaign we're going for a
million we're not we're not going to do
that
but it does raise interesting issues
around hypocrisy around business models
in this area and of course rebel wisdom
our business model is we we sustain
ourselves through and memberships we
sustain ourselves through an online
course that we've just put together but
obviously we're opening ourselves up to
accusations of hypocrisy I'm open to
criticism and look forward to seeing
where this goes it's okay
you